A Guide to the Lillian Adams collection FA1278
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lillian Adams collection
1916-1947
Rockefeller Archive Center
Adams, Lillian
FA1278
0.47 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Lillian Adams worked as a secretary for the General Education Board; after her retirement she collected and maintained materials related to various aspects of the Rockefeller family, institutions with Rockefeller and GEB connections, as well as items of personal interest.
Scope and Contents
The records of the Lillian Adams collection covers various aspects of her personal life and chronicles the important members and activities of the General Education Board, the International Education Board, and the Rockefeller Foundation from the years 1916 through 1947 intermittently.
Arrangement
Chronological.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accessioned by RAC in 2006, as 2006:060.
- The Rockefeller Foundation, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Meeting Docket and yearly review.
- General Education Board, 1916, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Summary report and meeting docket.
- International Education Board, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Report of activities and meeting docket.
- Photographs, 1924-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Charles Evans Hughes, 1924, 1944, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Newspaper articles.
- Mother Alphonsa, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Wallace Buttrick, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Newspaper articles, letter, obituaries and poem.
- Adams personal correspondence, 1928-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cartoons, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Political cartoons.
- News Clippings, 1943, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Owen D. Young, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Newspaper clippings
- University of Chicago, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Newspaper article, pamphlet
- Flexner family, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Newspaper article.
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Sketches, pamphlets.